[{"id": "5fe699e120565ad31a57c74d", "question": "Father Damien ministered to lepers on which Hawaiian Island?", "answer": "Molokai", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7ef", "question": "What vegetable secretes a psychotropic fluid called \"lactucarium\"?", "answer": "Lettuce", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a735", "question": "What city's buildings include the John Hancock Center and the Amoco Building?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e7", "question": "What is the longest one syllable word in the English language?", "answer": "Screeched", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffe4bd247818f5674af01b4", "question": "What is the name of the book the movie \"Goodfellas\" is based on?", "answer": "\"Wiseguy: Life in a Mafia Family\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af5c", "question": "Who developed the first modern set of headphones?", "answer": "Nathaniel Baldwin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b559e662d71a53650ff8", "question": "In Jane Austen's \"Pride and Prejudice,\" what is Mr. Darcy's first name?", "answer": "Fitzwilliam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a744", "question": "Yellowstone National Park protects the wilderness of what mountain chain?", "answer": "Rocky Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c3e9a56ebfabb9c85d8a97a", "question": "What name is given to the broad gap between the Saturn's A ring and B ring?", "answer": "The Cassini Division", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad7eab7b24f84e0b9f9ffd7", "question": "In the port of which city was the Greenpeace flagship Rainbow Warrior sunk in 1985?", "answer": "Auckland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a67a", "question": "The city of Chattanooga is located in which state?", "answer": "Tennessee", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e5", "question": "What were 2 out of 3 of Andrew Lloyd Webbers wives called?", "answer": "Sarah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a9d720565ad31a57c80b", "question": "The \"Star-Spangled Banner\" was written during which war?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad15", "question": "Who is the founder of Carthage?", "answer": "Dido", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b323", "question": "Who served as the head of the Soviet Union from 1922 to 1924?", "answer": "Vladimir Lenin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6670ba5bfecdd737e086a", "question": "What US state was the first to ban drivers from talking on handheld devices?", "answer": "New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a818", "question": "After Central Park was completed, New York City's 4th Avenue, above 32nd Street, was renamed what?", "answer": "Park Avenue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e38ceb0f6c8a670a7957c53", "question": "What actor has been killed by an Alien, a Predator, and a Terminator?", "answer": "Bill Paxton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf5", "question": "Which state was the first to ratify the 13th Amendment to abolish slavery?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a87620565ad31a57c7f5", "question": "Which U.S. state ignored Prohibition?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae9363574a5ce6b56b823a", "question": "What was Queen Victoria's first name?", "answer": "Alexandrina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b32e", "question": "What was the leading cause of death in the late 19th century?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c541", "question": "Icthyologists study what?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339655", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who invented the drink \"The Flaming Moe\"?", "answer": "Homer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b53101dd7bf43be5e7cc", "question": "What is the name for the process of electing a Pope?", "answer": "Conclave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a25efc56682715b82711cd8", "question": "Which Canadian province was responsible for producing the weekly newpaper publication \"Photo Journal\" until 1981?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e5", "question": "The Khyber pass joins which\u00a0two countries?", "answer": "Afghanistan and Pakistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0d", "question": "What is the capital of Comoros?", "answer": "Moroni", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2c7", "question": "Who played the role of J. D. Lutz on the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "John Lutz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029db7cad1ec93f27df751", "question": "What popular French apple brandy is made by distilling cider made from selected apples?", "answer": "Calvados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb5c", "question": "How old was the Elephant Man when he died?", "answer": "27", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8a", "question": "What\u2019s the Hungarian word for red pepper?", "answer": "Paprika", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ddc", "question": "Who played the Dark Knight in the movie \"Batman Forever\"?", "answer": "Val Kilmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f9", "question": "Which country were the 1992 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338968", "question": "What nursery rhyme character was arachnophobic?", "answer": "Little Miss Muffet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76e9beec85e375820b2de", "question": "What is the biggest country without a river?", "answer": "Saudi Arabia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4d", "question": "What type of device was the first Sony-branded product, released in 1955?", "answer": "Transistor Radio", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86c", "question": "What disease, caused by the bacteria Y. pestis, is spread by fleas and rats?", "answer": "Bubonic plague", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339710", "question": "Who played the role of Moses in the 1950s movie \"The Ten Commandments\"?", "answer": "Charlton Heston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be00", "question": "What feline was the first-ever character balloon in the Macy's Thanksgiving Day Parade?", "answer": "Felix the Cat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c75f", "question": "In what year did the Soviet Union launch its first Sputnik satellite?", "answer": "1957", "category": "science"}, {"id": "590678ebff9c0647b50a804e", "question": "What month, in 2016, did the World Trade Organization announce an outbreak of the Zika virus?", "answer": "January", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fae", "question": "Who composed the music for the opera \"The Tales of Hoffman\"?", "answer": "Jacques Offenbach", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58dba51e874c93a3298b214c", "question": "What country is credited with inventing the modern, self-igniting match?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed9", "question": "Whose famous balloon says \"State Fair Omaha\" on the outside?", "answer": "The Wizard of Oz's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe766c3eec85e375820b289", "question": "What capital city is the only one located on the equator?", "answer": "Quito, Ecuador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c679", "question": "What is the main source of food for the Bald Eagle?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7388feec85e375820b263", "question": "Which country is known as the Land of White Elephant?", "answer": "Thailand", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2af", "question": "What is the Scoville unit a measure of?", "answer": "The spicy heat of a chili pepper.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8aa4ec223966ae8f8833", "question": "Who ended his final 60 Minutes segment by saying \"if you do see me in a restaurant, please, just let me eat my dinner\"?", "answer": "Andy Rooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ac", "question": "Julia Roberts and Hugh Grant were paired in what romantic comedy?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b3", "question": "N2O is more commonly known as what?", "answer": "Laughing gas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c77d03224f0f7a362efd551", "question": "Who released an album called \"Don't Shoot Me I'm Only the Piano Player\" in 1973?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a1e1ca3b5a031299b745734", "question": "What is used to flavour Kriek lambic?", "answer": "Cherries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51b7aff04d658268c930e", "question": "What singers lure sailors to crash on the rocks with their songs?", "answer": "Circe warned Odysseus of the Sirens, bird-like women whose beautiful singing caused sailors to crash to their death.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ccb", "question": "What nursery rhyme character \"kissed the girls and made them cry\"?", "answer": "Georgy Porgy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b06be662d71a53650fc8", "question": "The four routes through the Vatican Museums all end at what showstopper?", "answer": "Michelangelo\u2019s Creation of Adam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd42", "question": "What hall of Famer played his entire major-league career for the Minnesota Twins?", "answer": "Kirby Puckett", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa5546ce05a3942286ebe", "question": "Which meal made the flight crew and some of the passengers ill in the comedy \"Airplane!\"?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cc7a877e98cb97778a26", "question": "Where was Breakneck Ridge in World War II?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e93917ccba3ffe45786c7", "question": "What is the \"Davy Lamp\" commonly referred to as?", "answer": "Miner's lamp", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c602", "question": "The moons of Uranus are named after characters from the works of what writers?", "answer": "Shakespeare and Alexander Pope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b1", "question": "In what 1950 film was the line \"Alright, Mr. Demille, I'm ready for my close-up\" spoken?", "answer": "Sunset Boulevard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394bf", "question": "What was the name of the cab company in the TV show \"Taxi\"?", "answer": "The Sunshine Cab Company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a1", "question": "In 1918, Woodrow Wilson addressed Congress with a speech laying out how many points?", "answer": "14", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904995ecf93664eb1048690", "question": "What is the capital of Antigua and Barbuda?", "answer": "St. John's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae4", "question": "What 2001 Rachael Leigh Cook film was based on an old Saturday morning cartoon series?", "answer": "Josie and the Pussycats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a382", "question": "What is the capital of the Netherlands?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af92", "question": "What song was originally called \"Defense of Fort M'Henry\"?", "answer": "The Star-Spangled Banner", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6f", "question": "What are described by the terms rep, challis and foulard?", "answer": "Neckties", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70d", "question": "What is the name given to glittery strings hung on Christmas trees?", "answer": "Tinsel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aacf", "question": "What is the second largest state in the US?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a566", "question": "The Redwood National Park is located in which US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b353", "question": "Who assassinated John Lennon?", "answer": "Mark David Chapman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe939506bd93ce3a4e5f68b", "question": "What plant do scientists use to clean up radioactive waste?", "answer": "Sunflowers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c17c", "question": "What is the fear of becoming cold called?", "answer": "Frigophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2c1", "question": "What US state is represented by the figures of Will Rogers and Sequoyah in the Capitol's Statuary Hall?", "answer": "Oklahoma", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3d", "question": "Which element appears ninth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Fluorine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c359", "question": "On which planet did the spacecraft Venus 8 land in 1972?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f025ff048f679a45aa97", "question": "Philematophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Kissing", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff0", "question": "What was Walt Disney's middle name?", "answer": "Elias", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339225", "question": "Who plays the role of Craig the puppeteer's wife in \"Being John Malkovich\"?", "answer": "Cameron Diaz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60077f9fbd51d85e222ab63e", "question": "What late 19th-century French painter was known for his pictures of ballet dancers?", "answer": "Edgar Degas is acknowledged as the master of drawing human figures in motion. The female ballet dancer became his favorite theme.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd4607e83c707845b215b", "question": "What famous actor turned down the role of Trinity in film \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Sandra Bullock turned down the role because she had the understanding that Will Smith was in the film.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015debafe83fe1f2a824b71", "question": "What weapon was developed in 1942 in a secret laboratory at Harvard University?", "answer": "Napalm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e73", "question": "What superteam includes Angel, Beast, Cyclops, Iceman and Marvel Girl?", "answer": "The X-Men", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd81d61d0de9af39e9d468e", "question": "Who was the only president to serve in both World Wars?", "answer": "Dwight D Eisenhower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa4023c73aa70ea0b70b08", "question": "From 1964 to 1980, what country was known as Rhodesia?", "answer": "Zimbabwe", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3a", "question": "Who's responsible for \"The Ballad of Billy the Kid\"?", "answer": "Billy Joel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa3", "question": "What TV family had a road manager named Reuben Kincaid?", "answer": "The Partridge Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a899b4160d398dc9cf7a69b", "question": "Egg Fu is the enemy of what superhero?", "answer": "Wonder Woman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ae866037f28483af1e7fdd2", "question": "What is the name of the band whose songs \"All Star\" and \"I\u2019m a Believer\" were featured in the 2001 film \"Shrek\"?", "answer": "Smash Mouth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c056", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Israel?", "answer": "Hoopoe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3bc", "question": "Which capital city was once known as Byzantium?", "answer": "Istanbul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b06f", "question": "What famous ship was sunk on May 7, 1915?", "answer": "The Lusitania", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c683", "question": "Which metal, in its purest form, has the highest melting point?", "answer": "Tungsten", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea35fdff048f679a45ab07", "question": "On what part of your body would you find the \"pinna\"?", "answer": "Ear", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa5", "question": "Whose real-life half sister, Lauren Bowles, played her sister on \"Watching Ellie\"?", "answer": "Julia Louis-Dreyfus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe259a9658e585fda9cfa42", "question": "What car feature did Ralph Teetor invent despite being blind?", "answer": "Cruise control", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72f", "question": "What beverage was the first American consumer product made widely available in the USSR?", "answer": "Pepsi-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ea", "question": "What is the most general and highest taxonomy rank of organisms?", "answer": "Domain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a15f", "question": "Who sang the theme to James Bond film \"For Your Eyes Only\"?", "answer": "Sheena Easton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c896", "question": "Where did the world's tallest bird, the giant moa, live until it went extinct around 1500?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e3", "question": "How old was the Elephant Man when he died?", "answer": "27", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebd", "question": "John Carpenter's \"Assault on Precinct 13\" is an homage to what classic Howard Hawks western?", "answer": "Rio Bravo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd9ee7e83c707845b217f", "question": "In the film \"The Shawshank Redemption,\" what did Andy write in the Bible for warden Norton to read after he had escaped?", "answer": "Dear Warden, you were right. Salvation lay within.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76ff8eec85e375820b2f1", "question": "In which city was the 2000 movie \"Gladiator\" filmed?", "answer": "Ouarzazate", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dfa", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek goddess Aphrodite?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded1deea2747c8aff16d37", "question": "Which musical do the songs \"Look at Me I'm Sandra Dee\" and \"Beauty School Dropout\" come from?", "answer": "Grease", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36c", "question": "Laika was the first ever dog to do what?", "answer": "Go into space", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e44", "question": "What American TV actor plays himself as a fallen angel in Wim Wenders' \"Wings of Desire\"?", "answer": "Peter Falk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b865", "question": "What is the only bird to be honored by its own year on the Chinese calendar?", "answer": "Rooster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fd", "question": "What toe is the foot reflexology pressure point for the head?", "answer": "The big one", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58f5660b33a95c66dc4fe75d", "question": "Which British opera festival was started in 1934?", "answer": "Glyndebourne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0df", "question": "Which pasta has a wide-ringed shape?", "answer": "Calamarata", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cdbd5e347d002c297e4e2", "question": "What meteorological significance is traditionally attached to cows lying down?", "answer": "Rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a227", "question": "What year did Puff Daddy record the song \"I'll Be Missing You\"?", "answer": "1997", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a1e", "question": "What city was the setting for the TV show \"Perfect Strangers\"?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b260", "question": "What did the US Federal Reserve system do a record seventeen consecutive times between 2004 and 2006?", "answer": "Raise interest rates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a076", "question": "In which TV series does Fred Savage play Kevin Arnold?", "answer": "The Wonder Years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa39b4c73aa70ea0b70ada", "question": "Which country does Denmark share its only land border with?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071f1e3745b36be73039e8", "question": "What is the full name of Em Cypress, Dana's sister and reviver, in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Martha Ann Cypress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015ec3dfe83fe1f2a824bfd", "question": "What artifact did Moses use to perform miracles and wonders in Egypt?", "answer": "A wooden staff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e07afe83fe1f2a824b8d", "question": "Which Old West figure became sports editor for the \"New York Morning Telegraph?\"", "answer": "William Barclay \"Bat\" Masterson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984d", "question": "What is the real name of the artist better known as Aphex Twin?", "answer": "Richard David James", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a997d61d1b4d384d5d69b", "question": "What year did the TV show \"Gunsmoke\" transition from a Black and White format to a Color format?", "answer": "1966", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e99e2ebfabb9c85d8a976", "question": "Berlin stands on the banks of which river?", "answer": "Spree", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339540", "question": "What show is \"The end of something simple. And the beginning of everything else\"?", "answer": "Dawson's Creek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a079", "question": "What record company did Berry Gordy Jr. start in 1959?", "answer": "Motown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcba", "question": "What model was married to musician Seal?", "answer": "Heidi Klum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b200", "question": "Whose US presidential campaign was targeted by the famous \"Daisy Girl\" negative TV ad?", "answer": "Barry Goldwater's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e38", "question": "In what film is General Jack Ripper obsessed with America's \"precious bodily fluids\"?", "answer": "Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59068223ff9c0647b50a809a", "question": "Which US Senator was nominated as Hillary Clinton\u2019s vice presidential running mate?", "answer": "Tim Kaine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b48", "question": "Whose epitaph reads: \"Quoth the Raven nevermore\"?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa8fa73838c5c8a417f40", "question": "What metal has excellent antimicrobial properties?", "answer": "Copper (Ancient Chinese people knew this and used to prescribe copper coins to treat certain diseases.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe937d86bd93ce3a4e5f679", "question": "Gynophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Women", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339474", "question": "In what city does the movie \"Mrs. Doubtfire\" take place?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b191", "question": "What year was Napoleon Bonaparte born?", "answer": "1769", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a16920565ad31a57c7a3", "question": "Who was president when the White House got its first computer?", "answer": "Jimmy Carter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d0", "question": "How many rivers does Saudi Arabia have?", "answer": "None", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ccf7944b37b32637bdc44bd", "question": "Who was Cesare Borgia's father?", "answer": "Pope Alexander VI", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6008ddf6f4f3bc4a292f8626", "question": "In what city did American colonists dress as Native Americans and dump an entire, expensive tea into the sea", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a3d", "question": "The 2002 film \"Confessions of a Dangerous Mind\" was based on the unauthorized autobiography of what former gameshow host?", "answer": "Chuck Barris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b2c", "question": "What painting was stolen in broad daylight from a museum in Oslo in 2004?", "answer": "The Scream", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84c", "question": "What symbol of peace surrounds the globe on the UN flag?", "answer": "Olive branch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339372", "question": "In the movie \"Batman\", what does the Joker call his secret ingredient?", "answer": "Smylex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a825", "question": "What large island lies about 300 miles due east of Mozambique?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c1", "question": "In atmospheres, what is the equivalent of 760 milimeters of Mercury (mmHg)?", "answer": "1 atm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1f", "question": "What place did Dante describe as having \"Abandon hope, all ye who enter here\" written over its doors?", "answer": "Hell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5aab2e2258d116dab4aecb3a", "question": "As what was Taiwan formerly known?", "answer": "Formosa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c207", "question": "Which country were the 1908 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339452", "question": "What were the children allergic to in the movie \"The Others\"?", "answer": "Light", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af75", "question": "What treaty ended the Mexican War?", "answer": "Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5977432a284458f1d7854427", "question": "Albert Einstein was offered the position of prime minister of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e0", "question": "What does a monophobe fear?", "answer": "Being alone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81c29d0de9af39e9d4680", "question": "What color was originally associated with St. Patrick\u2019s Day?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cee", "question": "Who wrote the collection of science fiction stories that made up the book \"I, Robot\"?", "answer": "Isaac Asimov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa550dc73aa70ea0b70b20", "question": "Hastings, England has a distinct May Day festival which is known as what?", "answer": "Jack in the Green", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a464", "question": "Mount Rushmore is located near which town in South Dakota?", "answer": "Keystone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339783", "question": "What album earned the Bee Gees a Grammy Award in 1978?", "answer": "Saturday Night Fever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8d5412b42d4a3561a9f00", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is the name of Francine\u2019s daughter?", "answer": "Jenny", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8ff3101dd7bf43be5e861", "question": "Who said, \"I find that the harder I work, the more luck I seem to have.\"?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b277", "question": "According to Betsy Ross' family, what was the first American flag made from?", "answer": "Hemp", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e15", "question": "What's the name of the flat, square prison that holds the Kryptonian criminals in the Superman movies?", "answer": "The Phantom Zone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6571aae7e414034b5aed6", "question": "Samuel Tilden, Grover Cleveland, Al Gore, and Hillary Clinton share what distinction among U.S. presidential candidates?", "answer": "They won the popular vote but lost the electoral college vote", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca7b", "question": "Who was the first dog in space?", "answer": "Laika", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971f", "question": "Which Australian played James Bond?", "answer": "George Lazenby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c246", "question": "What date did man first land on the moon?", "answer": "July 20, 1969", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c2", "question": "Which planet spins on a nearly horizontal axis, as opposed to all the others which  spin on a vertical axis?", "answer": "Uranus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e7", "question": "What singer first hit #1 in 1984 with \"Caribbean Queen (No More Love on the Run)\"?", "answer": "Billy Ocean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b148", "question": "Who was the first US President born outside the 13 original states?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln,", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339637", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Esmeralda?", "answer": "Quasimodo's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a739", "question": "Klamath Lake is the largest lake in which US state?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af9a", "question": "Which U.S. President ended his country's participation in the Vietnam War?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cefc0ae948005ec986edcde", "question": "Who is the fifth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Vivi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab959c86faa38a764be517", "question": "Before starting to produce cars in the late 1940s, what did SAAB originally manufacture?", "answer": "Aircrafts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b619", "question": "Who was the first female to be featured on the front of a Wheaties box?", "answer": "Mary Lou Retton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339469", "question": "Who drinks Tim's lava lamp in the 1999 movie \"My Favourite Martian\"?", "answer": "Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5921fc96a4edfd43a087adc0", "question": "Sweet Baby Broccoli is another name for what vegetable?", "answer": "Broccolini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb60665ff7d326b622a93", "question": "Under what title was Agatha Christie's \"Murder on the Orient Express\" first published in the US?", "answer": "Murder on the Calais Coach", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59675f432b59efe0e9417e99", "question": "What animal can dig a tunnel 300 feet long in just one night?", "answer": "A mole", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af7", "question": "Which character killed Captain Ahab?", "answer": "Moby-Dick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4af249076251badbeabe", "question": "Ruby Bridges became the first Black student to do what?", "answer": "At six-years-old, Ruby Bridges was the first Black child to be integrated into an all-white school in New Orleans in 1960.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29a", "question": "What US politician was named for Julius Caesar?", "answer": "J. C. Watts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a142", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Gasoline Alley\"?", "answer": "Rod Stewart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6aa4820565ad31a57c814", "question": "Who first developed stereophonic sound?", "answer": "Alan Blumlein", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339074", "question": "Which 1965 science fiction novel featured the Houses of Corrino, Harkonnen, and Atreides?", "answer": "Dune", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c339877e98cb97778992", "question": "What causes the gory-looking red tint of Antarctica\u2019s Blood Falls?", "answer": "Iron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "591c3729815febcc896f926e", "question": "What is a group of mallards in flight called?", "answer": "A Sord", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea48f2ff048f679a45abb5", "question": "Pes planus refers to which condition?", "answer": "Flat feet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e94d0ff5ea27d7a1303aed3", "question": "Is the cucumber a fruit or a vegetable?", "answer": "Fruit", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c058", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Japan?", "answer": "Green pheasant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac35", "question": "Which of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World was alive?", "answer": "The Hanging Gardens of Babylon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7e87cb24f84e0b9f9ffc4", "question": "What process involves the heating of milk to a temperature of about 70 degrees Celsius?", "answer": "Pasteurisation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b85", "question": "What\u2019s the ballet term for a 360 degree turn on one foot?", "answer": "A Pirouette", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef5f566ce05a3942286e41", "question": "Who was the highest paid athlete of 2018?", "answer": "Floyd Mayweather", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afca", "question": "With what animal's pelts did the Plains Indians traditionally build their teepees?", "answer": "Bison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb3", "question": "How many symphonies did Beethoven compose?", "answer": "9", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b993", "question": "What number was retired by the Chicago Bulls to honor Michael Jordan?", "answer": "23", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95a", "question": "The surrealist poet Leon-Paul Fargue honored which popular French product with the title \"les pieds de Dieu\"?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e8a89a1404ad935a7e1a640", "question": "Which English soccer team's mascot is a canary?", "answer": "Norwich City", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5de", "question": "Saginaw Bay opens into what body of water?", "answer": "Lake Huron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc7", "question": "The dish, Cullen Skink, originates from which country?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c22a", "question": "The fear of punishment is known as what?", "answer": "Poinephobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e3", "question": "Which two classic Monopoly game tokens are articles that can be worn?", "answer": "The shoe and the top hat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396bb", "question": "What country was the setting for the 2009 movie \"The Hurt Locker\"?", "answer": "Iraq", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d7", "question": "What made-for-TV movie starred Alfre Woodard as Eunice Evers?", "answer": "Miss Evers' Boys", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339612", "question": "In which movie does Woody Allen awaken 200 years in the future?", "answer": "Sleeper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b05", "question": "What year was Charles Darwin's work, \"On the Origin of Species\", published?", "answer": "1859", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e8", "question": "Greenland is a dependency of what European country?", "answer": "Denmark", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c11a877e98cb97778972", "question": "Which countries share the International Peace Garden?", "answer": "USA and Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5c77d47124f0f7a362efd557", "question": "In the novel and movie \"Hitchhikers Guide to The Galaxy,\" what is the most important thing a hitchhiker can carry?", "answer": "A towel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899bed60d398dc9cf7a6a2", "question": "In the body, what is the CNS?", "answer": "Central Nervous System", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4e", "question": "Who wrote \"Gulliver's Travels\"?", "answer": "Jonathan Swift", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae58", "question": "The Minutemen fought during what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b719", "question": "What carol contains the words \"Fa-la-la-la-la-la-la-la-la\"", "answer": "Deck the Halls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7e0", "question": "What year saw the opening of the first Starbucks store?", "answer": "1971", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cd9d5e347d002c297e4cf", "question": "What became the tallest building in London after its official opening in October 1965?", "answer": "Post Office Tower", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea809bff048f679a45ac1a", "question": "What does velociraptor mean in Latin?", "answer": "Swift plunderer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b6", "question": "Which war was said to be largely responsible for reviving Samuel Colt's firearms business?", "answer": "The Mexican-American War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928b", "question": "\"Highlander\" tells the story of which immortal swords-man?", "answer": "Connor MacLeod", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390de", "question": "What is the name of the leading female singer in an opera?", "answer": "Prima donna", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acea", "question": "Which president's wife helped fund the war effort by auctioning wool from sheep grazing on the White House lawn?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f153ff048f679a45aab0", "question": "Alektorophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Chickens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb12", "question": "In what year did Jimmy Buffett open his first Margaritaville restaurant?", "answer": "1985", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb64", "question": "What rank in the US Army is just above the rank of First Lieutenant?", "answer": "Captain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af95", "question": "In what year did the Spanish Civil War begin?", "answer": "1936", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015ef03fe83fe1f2a824c0c", "question": "In what year did Christmas become a federal holiday in the United States?", "answer": "1870", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e11", "question": "What American literary character's real name is Lula Mae Barnes?", "answer": "Holly Golightly", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af7", "question": "Not counting Elvis, what actor is mentioned by name in the Shania Twain song \"That Don't Impress Me Much\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ad", "question": "What was the Asian nation of Myanmar known as prior to 1989?", "answer": "Burma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60173bcf44491cbd7c5a17a0", "question": "The words of poet Emma Lazarus are on which U.S. monument?", "answer": "Her line, \"Give me your tired, your poor, your huddled masses yearning to breathe free,\" are on the base of the Statue of Liberty.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc8", "question": "Who had a surprise cameo as \"Agent M\" in \"Men in Black II\"?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbba", "question": "During what year's Summer Olympics did swimmer Mark Spitz win seven gold medals?", "answer": "1972", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feccbabec223966ae8f889e", "question": "When Jackie Chan's foot catches on fire in \"The Legend of Drunken Master\", how does he put it out?", "answer": "Kicks water that's thrown on the set", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a162af7f01ec323f8491726", "question": "After leaving 10000 Maniacs, who released her first solo album \"Tigerlily\" in 1995?", "answer": "Natalie Merchant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd6bbe347d002c297e4bc", "question": "Morten Harket is the lead singer of which band?", "answer": "A-ha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a31", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1962 award-winning film \"Lawrence of Arabia\"?", "answer": "Peter O\u2019Toole", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5cb66ce05a3942286e24", "question": "Which Doors song is about Jim Morrison\u2019s relationship with Pamela Courson?", "answer": "\"Queen of the Highway\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cd39bb53d1af658864e7", "question": "What gives traditional eggnog its frothy texture?", "answer": "Whipped eggs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58be2d418faf425cf37add7c", "question": "The American rock band, \"The Black Keys\", hails from which US state?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9a9", "question": "What mountain is the tallest point in Japan?", "answer": "Fuji", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd81c98d0de9af39e9d4686", "question": "What U.S. president was nicknamed \"Napoleon of the Stump?\"", "answer": "James K. Polk", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c48c", "question": "What garden flower's name literally means \"nose twister\"?", "answer": "Nasturtium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015effcfe83fe1f2a824c0f", "question": "Where was Christmas first celebrated?", "answer": "Rome -- it was first celebrated in 336 A.D.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917f", "question": "Who is the Kindergarten Cop?", "answer": "Arnold Schwarzenneger", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa564ec73aa70ea0b70b29", "question": "What type of dancing is usually performed in conjunction with May Day celebrations in England?", "answer": "Morris dance", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4d9a0708b8581f80b092b9", "question": "Which Bond actor passed away on May 23, 2017?", "answer": "Roger Moore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66ae952a821ff76ae8b0b", "question": "Confucianism effectively became the common philosophy of the Chinese empire during which dynasty?", "answer": "Han Dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4b1be06d333868d34d6d4", "question": "Who commanded the French army in India during the Seven Years War?", "answer": "Dupleix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5971e06089261e916c8e09ab", "question": "What US state was \"Steak 'n Shake\" founded in?", "answer": "Illinois", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa1", "question": "What legendary jazz trumpeter was nicknamed \"Satchmo\"?", "answer": "Louie Armstrong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b47501dd7bf43be5e7c0", "question": "What ingredient makes up at least 51% of bourbon mash?", "answer": "Corn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c56c", "question": "Phobos is the name of one of the moons of which planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcdb", "question": "How many squares on a side is a daily \"New York Times\" crossword puzzle?", "answer": "15", "category": "general"}]